Yu Guo

(update: 11/03/2023)

https://tflsguoyu.github.io/

tflsguoyu@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

I am currently a **Senior Graphics Researcher** at **Tencent America** in New York. My background is mainly focused on **Computer Graphics**, specially in **Physics-based Rendering** and **Inverse-rendering**. I am also interested in **Material Capture** by using **Generative AI Models** or **Procedural Models**. How to decompose **light/shadow** and material properties from a 3D model (Mesh/NeRF) and make it **relightable** are what I am willing to solve. Besides, I am interested in any project related to **Meta Human**.

EDUCATION

University of California, Irvine

Irvine, CA, US

Ph.D in Computer Science

Sept. 2016 - Aug. 2021

Dissertation: Multi-scale Appearance Modeling of Complex Materials.

Advisor: Shuang Zhao

University of Chinese Academy of Sciences

Beijing & Shenzhen, China

M.S. in Computer Science

Sept. 2010 - Jul. 2013

Thesis: GPU-based Soft Body Deformation with Nonlinear Finite Element Method.

Advisor: Pheng Ann Heng (CUHK)

Central South University

Changsha, China

B.S. in Mathematics and Applied Mathematics

Sept. 2006 – Jul. 2010

Thesis: Forces Distribution with Fractal Theory in High Velocity Compaction Technology.

WORKING EXPERIENCES

Tencent America

New York, NY, US

Senior Researcher at Pixel Lab

Jan. 2023 – present

Working on AIGC related projects: genAI, 3D reconstruction, segmentation, image-based relighting.

Manager: Changxi Zheng

Tencent America

Playa Vista, CA, US

Senior Researcher at Graphics and Vision Team

Sept. 2021 - Dec. 2022

Working on Volumetric rendering in UE; Texture map delighting, shadow and highlight removal.

Manager: Bo Yang

Facebook Reality Lab

Sausalito, CA, US

Research Intern at Monaco Team

July. 2020 - Sept. 2020

Working on Eye caustics rendering and its inverse problem.

Advisor: Christophe Hery, Olivier Maury

Adobe Research

San Jose, CA, US

Research Intern at Emerging Graphics Group

July. 2019 - Sept. 2019

Working on Material capture and estimation.

Advisor: Miloš Hašan, Kalyan Sunkavalli

Megvii (Face++) Research USA

Redmond, WA, US

 $Research\ Intern$

July. 2018 – Sept. 2018

Working on Human face shadow/highlight removal and face relighting.

Advisor: Jue Wang

Autodesk

San Francisco, CA, US

Research Intern at Core Rendering team

July. 2017 - Sept. 2017

Working on efficient volumetric rendering of 3D-printing materials.

Advisor: Miloš Hašan

Nanyang Technological University

Singapore

Research Associate at BeingThere Centre (BTC), IMI

Oct. 2013 – Mar. 2016

(BTC is a US\$18 million international research project on 3D Telepresence and Virtual Reality between ETH (Markus Gross), UNC (Henry Fuchs) and NTU (Nadia Magnenat Thalmann).)

Working on stereo rendering; physical-based video manipulation; virtual try-on system for prescription glasses.

Collaborators: Miriam Reiner, Jean-Charles Bazin, Tobias Martin, Claudia Plüss, Pierre-Yves Laf-

font, Qian Zhang

Advisor: Tat-Jen Cham

Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology

Shenzhen, China

Research Assistant at HCI lab

Sept. 2011 - Jul. 2013

Working on mesh processing; soft body simulation; virtual surgery; CUDA acceleration.

Advisor: Pheng-Ann Heng, Yongming Xie

Publications

"Woven Fabric Capture from a Single Photo" by Wenhua Jin, Beibei Wang, Milos Hasan, Yu Guo, Steve Marschner and Lingqi Yan. SIGGRAPH Asia '22

"Beyond Mie Theory: Systematic Computation of Bulk Scattering Parameters based on Microphysical Wave Optics" by Yu Guo, Adrian Jarabo and Shuang Zhao. ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG), 2021 (presented at SIGGRAPH Asia '21).

"MaterialGAN: Reflectance Capture using a Generative SVBRDF Model" by Yu Guo, Cameron Smith, Miloš Hašan, Kalyan Sunkavalli and Shuang Zhao. ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG), 2020 (presented at SIGGRAPH Asia '20).

"A Bayesian Inference Framework for Procedural Material Parameter Estimation" by Yu Guo, Miloš Hašan, Lingqi Yan and Shuang Zhao. Computer Graphics Forum (CGF), 2020 (presented at Pacific Graphics '20).

"Position-Free Monte Carlo Simulation for Arbitrary Layered BSDFs" by Yu Guo, Miloš Hašan and Shuang Zhao. ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG), 2018 (presented at SIGGRAPH Asia '18).

"A Virtual Try-on System for Prescription Eyeglasses" by Qian Zhang, Yu Guo, Pierre-Yves Laffont, Tobias Martin, and Markus Gross. *IEEE Computer Graphics and Applications (CG&A)*, 2017.

"3D Faces are Recognized More Accurately and Faster than 2D Faces, but with Similar Inversion Effects" by Derric Eng, Belle Yick, Yu Guo, Hong Xu, Miriam Reiner, Tat-Jen Cham, and Annabel Chen. Vision Research, 2017.

"Physically Based Video Editing" by Jean-Charles Bazin, Claudia Plüss (Kuster), Yu Guo, Tobias Martin, Alec Jacobson, and Markus Gross. Computer Graphics Forum (CGF), 2016 (presented at Pacific Graphics '16).

"GPU Accelerated CBCT Reconstruction from Few Views with SART and TV Regularization" by Ping Liu, Lin Shi, Defeng Wang, Yu Guo, Jianying Li, Jing Qin, and Pheng-Ann Heng. International Workshop on High Performance Computing for Biomedical Image Analysis (HPC-MICCAI), 2013.

"Real-time Hand Detection Based on Multi-stage HOG-SVM Classifier" by Jiang Guo, Jun Cheng, Jianxin Pang, and Yu Guo. International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), 2013.

"A GPU-Accelerated Finite Element Solver for Simulation of Soft-Body Deformation" by

Yu Guo, Jianying Li, Ping Liu, Qiong Wang, and Jing Qin. International Conference on Information and Automation (ICIA), 2013.

"A Survey on Simulation of Soft Tissue Deformation in Virtual Surgery(In Chinese)" by Yu Guo, Jing Qin. Journal of Integration Technology (JIT), 2013.

"Fall over or Sliding down?" by Yu Guo. SIGGRAPH Asia (Poster), 2012.

"A Master-Slave Robotic Simulator Based on GPUDirect" by Jianying Li, Yu Guo, Heye Zhang, Yongming Xie. International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2012.

Reviews

TOG, CGF, SIGGRAPH, SIGGRAPH Asia, EG, PG